<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Civic Open Data</title>
    <link>https://civicopendata.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Civic Open Data</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 20:55:06 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://civicopendata.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Thank you!</title>
      <link>https://civicopendata.com/thank-you-newsletter-question/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 20:55:06 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://civicopendata.com/thank-you-newsletter-question/</guid>
      <description>Thank you for answering my question.
This will help me make the newsletter even better for you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Volume 4: This Week in Civic Tech/Open Data</title>
      <link>https://civicopendata.com/posts/this-week-in-civic-tech-open-data-wk-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2019 15:34:24 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://civicopendata.com/posts/this-week-in-civic-tech-open-data-wk-7/</guid>
      <description>This week includes data visualisations about Trees in New York, Wildfires in California, Housing in Boston and Scooters in San Diego.
I&amp;rsquo;m still figuring out the best approach to it, and if you have any suggestions please let me know :)
Visualizations NYC Street Tree Map This one is not totally new but worth checking out and sharing.
 The New York City Street Tree Map brings New York City’s urban forest to your fingertips.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Volume 3: This week in Civic Tech/Open Data</title>
      <link>https://civicopendata.com/posts/this-week-in-civic-tech-open-data-wk-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2019 14:05:41 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://civicopendata.com/posts/this-week-in-civic-tech-open-data-wk-5/</guid>
      <description>Volume 3 of my weekly roundup of visualizations, news and tweets in Civic Tech. The week was packed with great civic visualiations and fewer articles. Topics include Snow Clearing in Canada, civil forfeiture in SC, Cincinatti Heroin Incidents and more.
Visualizations This week we had plenty of great civic data visualizations and data stories from newspapers. That really made me happy :smile:
Snow clearing complaints in Kitchener Mike Boos did an excellent visualization about sidewalk snow clearing complaints from 2008-2018 using Open Data from City of Kitchener, Ontario, Canada</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Volume 2: This Week in Civic Tech/Open Data</title>
      <link>https://civicopendata.com/posts/this-week-in-civic-tech-open-data-wk4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 11:41:44 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://civicopendata.com/posts/this-week-in-civic-tech-open-data-wk4/</guid>
      <description>Week 2 of my collection of interesting things happening around Civic Tech, Open Data and Open Government. Still working on the right formats, length and time frame. If you have suggestions please get in touch, would love to know your opinion.
Visualizations How Americans Commute to Work A few maps on how Americans commute to work.
Visualization
Pollution risk for Chicago Neighborhoods A static map created by the Natural Resources Defense Council (NRDC) which shows the Chicago neighborhoods most at risk from pollution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Volume 1: This week in Civic Tech/Open Data</title>
      <link>https://civicopendata.com/posts/this-week-in-civic-tech-open-data-wk3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 18:51:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://civicopendata.com/posts/this-week-in-civic-tech-open-data-wk3/</guid>
      <description>This is the first post of an effort I want to make to collect all interesting articles, visualizations and data releases from the last 7 days. I will publish them on Fridays here and will email them out.
This week has a lot of stuff in it because it is the first of the series. I&amp;rsquo;m still figuring out how to divide the content into sections. If you have suggestions, please get in touch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://civicopendata.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 12:09:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://civicopendata.com/about/</guid>
      <description>What is this all about?
I searched for a place to share content I create or think about when working with Civic Open Data. I wanted to have a place where I can write about Open Data and Civic Tech as well as share Data Visualisations I created with Open Data.
This is the place I want to share it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Louisville Bird Data published</title>
      <link>https://civicopendata.com/posts/lousiville-bird/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 06:08:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://civicopendata.com/posts/lousiville-bird/</guid>
      <description>The City of Louisville in Kentucky is the first city to publish Bird Scooter Data as CSV in their Open Data Portal. They updated their data three times already, so we should be in for a treat with monthly updates.
We have to thank the City of Louisville and Bird for releasing data so that we can finally study how people use scooters in cities.
This is just a partial analysis since we only have data for one city and only for a limited time frame.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gov Data</title>
      <link>https://civicopendata.com/posts/govdata/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2018 16:08:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://civicopendata.com/posts/govdata/</guid>
      <description>While I was developing my government funded prototype „Automated City Open Data Census“ for Germany I was so deep into scrambling with metadata that I decided to take a closer look at the types and formats that get published.
So I used the CKAN API to get basic data from CKAN about licenses used, data formats and categories.
A few not so supering facts are that not fully open licenes still dominate the field and PDF is the most published data format in Germany.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>