<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Civic Open Data</title>
    <link>https://civicopendata.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Civic Open Data</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2019 17:51:49 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://civicopendata.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Volume 9: This Week in Civic Tech/Open Data</title>
      <link>https://civicopendata.com/posts/this-week-in-civic-tech-open-data-wk11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2019 17:51:49 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://civicopendata.com/posts/this-week-in-civic-tech-open-data-wk11/</guid>
      <description>Not much was going on last week, so this roundup will be short and include some more data-driven journalism. The Baltimore Sun is busy producing data-driven stories, and I love that they share their process and code. The National Geographic is known for beautiful visualizations, and they show it off again :)
Visualizations The Shape of cities A TALE OF FIVE CITIES AND HOW THEY GREW
 Rail, roads, and real estate play a role in the physical shape of cities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Volume 8: This Week in Civic Tech/Open Data</title>
      <link>https://civicopendata.com/posts/this-week-in-civic-tech-open-data-wk10/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 07:02:09 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://civicopendata.com/posts/this-week-in-civic-tech-open-data-wk10/</guid>
      <description>Visualizations Syracuse Snow Map What I love about this project is this comprehensive writeup of how they built it: http://www.innovatesyracuse.com/blog/snowplowmapdevelopment
And everything is Open Source on GitHub available for everyone to check out the code or reimplement it.
It would be great if they included the link to the explanation on the map somewhere. The colors, especially the one for &amp;ldquo;Not yet plowed&amp;rdquo; does not work great with the basemap.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Toronto High Rise Building inspection</title>
      <link>https://civicopendata.com/posts/toronto-high-rise-building-inspection/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 07:03:27 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://civicopendata.com/posts/toronto-high-rise-building-inspection/</guid>
      <description>In Volume 6 of my weekly roundup I highlighted some newly released data from the city of Toronto about Highrisers Building Inspection data. The newspaper that reported about it was not happy about the format that it was available. And I agree it is not very searchable or does not provide too much information.
But: They use an API to show the data in the table. And it turns out, I can use the API as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Volume 7: This Week in Civic Tech/Open Data</title>
      <link>https://civicopendata.com/posts/this-week-in-civic-tech-open-data-wk9/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2019 16:53:05 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://civicopendata.com/posts/this-week-in-civic-tech-open-data-wk9/</guid>
      <description>This week seem to be a slow week in visualizations and articles. But still, there were some interesting pieces. They mostly relate to transit but all cover different angles. We have Subway desserts in NY, runner data displaying segregation in Baltimore and a new way to visualize transit trips.
Next week will include all the awesome things that happened on Saturday, March 2nd around the world on Open Data Day!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Volume 6: This Week in Civic Tech/Open Data</title>
      <link>https://civicopendata.com/posts/this-week-in-civic-tech-open-data-wk8/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2019 16:53:05 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://civicopendata.com/posts/this-week-in-civic-tech-open-data-wk8/</guid>
      <description>This week we have more articles than usual from newspapers using data-driven journalism. I really like that part of journalism and hope that more newspapers go that route. Especially the ones that publish their analysis so it can be reproduced or other newspapers can adapt it for their city.
Visualizations Chicago Middle-class is shrinking. WBEZ Radio Chicago uses data and graphs from the Nathalie P. Voorhees Center for Neighborhood and Community Improvement at the University of Illinois at Chicago to produce an article with the title: &amp;ldquo;The Middle Class Is Shrinking Everywhere — In Chicago It’s Almost Gone&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Volume 5: This Week in Civic Tech/Open Data</title>
      <link>https://civicopendata.com/posts/this-week-in-civic-tech-open-data-wk7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2019 17:39:46 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://civicopendata.com/posts/this-week-in-civic-tech-open-data-wk7/</guid>
      <description>This week is heavy on visualisations and maps again. Lot&amp;rsquo;s of interesting things were released last week.
Visualizations Fighting Opioid Misuse by Monitoring Community Health This is a cool project by the City of Tempe, AZ using ArcGIS storymap and dashboard to explain opioids in wastewater collection.
If you only look at the dashboard, it is not immediately obvious why only three areas have graphs, and three don‘t. But if you read the story map, it will be explained.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Volume 4: This Week in Civic Tech/Open Data</title>
      <link>https://civicopendata.com/posts/this-week-in-civic-tech-open-data-wk-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2019 15:34:24 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://civicopendata.com/posts/this-week-in-civic-tech-open-data-wk-6/</guid>
      <description>This week includes data visualisations about Trees in New York, Wildfires in California, Housing in Boston and Scooters in San Diego.
I&amp;rsquo;m still figuring out the best approach to it, and if you have any suggestions please let me know :)
Visualizations NYC Street Tree Map This one is not totally new but worth checking out and sharing.
 The New York City Street Tree Map brings New York City’s urban forest to your fingertips.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Volume 3: This week in Civic Tech/Open Data</title>
      <link>https://civicopendata.com/posts/this-week-in-civic-tech-open-data-wk-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2019 14:05:41 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://civicopendata.com/posts/this-week-in-civic-tech-open-data-wk-5/</guid>
      <description>Volume 3 of my weekly roundup of visualizations, news and tweets in Civic Tech. The week was packed with great civic visualiations and fewer articles. Topics include Snow Clearing in Canada, civil forfeiture in SC, Cincinatti Heroin Incidents and more.
Visualizations This week we had plenty of great civic data visualizations and data stories from newspapers. That really made me happy :smile:
Snow clearing complaints in Kitchener Mike Boos did an excellent visualization about sidewalk snow clearing complaints from 2008-2018 using Open Data from City of Kitchener, Ontario, Canada</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Volume 2: This Week in Civic Tech/Open Data</title>
      <link>https://civicopendata.com/posts/this-week-in-civic-tech-open-data-wk4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 11:41:44 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://civicopendata.com/posts/this-week-in-civic-tech-open-data-wk4/</guid>
      <description>Week 2 of my collection of interesting things happening around Civic Tech, Open Data and Open Government. Still working on the right formats, length and time frame. If you have suggestions please get in touch, would love to know your opinion.
Visualizations How Americans Commute to Work A few maps on how Americans commute to work.
Visualization
Pollution risk for Chicago Neighborhoods A static map created by the Natural Resources Defense Council (NRDC) which shows the Chicago neighborhoods most at risk from pollution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Volume 1: This week in Civic Tech/Open Data</title>
      <link>https://civicopendata.com/posts/this-week-in-civic-tech-open-data-wk3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 18:51:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://civicopendata.com/posts/this-week-in-civic-tech-open-data-wk3/</guid>
      <description>This is the first post of an effort I want to make to collect all interesting articles, visualizations and data releases from the last 7 days. I will publish them on Fridays here and will email them out.
This week has a lot of stuff in it because it is the first of the series. I&amp;rsquo;m still figuring out how to divide the content into sections. If you have suggestions, please get in touch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Louisville Bird Data published</title>
      <link>https://civicopendata.com/posts/lousiville-bird/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 06:08:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://civicopendata.com/posts/lousiville-bird/</guid>
      <description>The City of Louisville in Kentucky is the first city to publish Bird Scooter Data as CSV in their Open Data Portal. They updated their data three times already, so we should be in for a treat with monthly updates.
We have to thank the City of Louisville and Bird for releasing data so that we can finally study how people use scooters in cities.
This is just a partial analysis since we only have data for one city and only for a limited time frame.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gov Data</title>
      <link>https://civicopendata.com/posts/govdata/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2018 16:08:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://civicopendata.com/posts/govdata/</guid>
      <description>While I was developing my government funded prototype „Automated City Open Data Census“ for Germany I was so deep into scrambling with metadata that I decided to take a closer look at the types and formats that get published.
So I used the CKAN API to get basic data from CKAN about licenses used, data formats and categories.
A few not so supering facts are that not fully open licenes still dominate the field and PDF is the most published data format in Germany.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>